Moonrise Kingdom is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Wes Anderson.
Set on an island off the coast of New England in the summer of 1965, Moonrise Kingdom tells the story of two
twelve-year-olds who fall in love, make a secret pact, and run away together into the wilderness.
As various authorities try to hunt them down, a violent storm is brewing off-shore – and the
peaceful island community is turned upside down in more ways than anyone can handle.
Sam Shakusky, played by Jared Gilman.
Suzy Bishop, played by Kara Hayward.
Captain Sharp, played by Bruce Willis.
Scout Master Ward, played by Edward Norton.
Mr. Bishop, played by Bill Murray.
Mrs. Bishop, played by Frances McDormand.
Moonrise Kingdom is a 2012 American coming-of-age comedy drama film directed by Wes Anderson, written by Anderson and Roman Coppola, and starring Bruce Willis,
Edward Norton, Bill Murray, Frances McDormand, Tilda Swinton, Jason Schwartzman, Bob Balaban, and introducing Jared Gilman and Kara Hayward.
Largely set on the fictional island of New Penzance somewhere off the coast of New England, it tells the story of an orphan boy (Gilman)
who escapes from a scouting camp to unite with his pen pal and love interest, a girl with aggressive tendencies (Hayward).
Feeling alienated from their guardians and shunned by their
peers, the lovers abscond to an isolated beach.
Meanwhile, the island's police captain (Willis) organizes a search
party of scouts and family members to locate the runaways.
In crafting their screenplay, Anderson and Coppola drew from personal experiences and memories of
childhood fantasies as well as films including Melody (1971) and The 400 Blows (1959).
Auditions for child actors took eight months, and filming took
place in Rhode Island over three months in 2011.
Moonrise Kingdom premiered at the 2012 Cannes Film Festival and received critical acclaim, with its themes of
young love, child sexuality, juvenile mental health, and the Genesis flood narrative being praised.
Critics cited the film's color palette and use of visual symmetry as well as the use of original
composition by Alexandre Desplat to supplement existing music by Benjamin Britten.
It was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay
and the Golden Globe for Best Musical or Comedy.
In 2016, the BBC included the film in its list of
greatest films of the twenty-first century.
The film explores themes of camping, hurricane, pen pals, coming of age, camp.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.